Guide to the Ernest Huffcut papers, 1883-1905.
Huffcut, Ernest papers, 1883-1905.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ernest Huffcut papers, 1883-1905.
18\01\129
Ernest W. Huffcutt
1 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal papers of Ernest Huffcut relating to his time at Cornell University. Includes publications and correspondence.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal papers of Ernest Huffcut relating to his time at Cornell University. Includes publications and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Huffcutt, Ernest W.; Batcheller, George Sherman, 1837-1908.; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Batcheller, George Sherman, 1837-1908; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918; Cornell University -- History.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Students
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cornell University Annals: The John DeWitt Warner Controversy, 1883 (Box 1)
  Scrapbook
- My Reminisces of Ezra Cornell: An Address Delivered Before The Cornell University on Founder's Day, January 11th, 1890, 1890-01-11 (Box 1)
  (Monograph) Pamphlet glued inside
- Ithaca and its Resources, 1883 (Box 1)
- The Tariff: Lectures by Honorable Ellis H. Roberts and Professor Henry C. Adams, 1884-02 (Box 1)
- Cornell University Annals, 1885 (Box 1)
- Reports, Proceedings, Etc., 1873-1899 (Box 1)
- Supplement to The Troy Daily Times, 1898 (Box 1)
- Class Day programs, 1886-1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Commencement material, 1886-1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1887-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Huffcut's publications, 1884-1900 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alumni material, 1884-1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Debate club material, 1894-1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Woodford prize contest programs, 1894-1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Five private proofs of Andrew Dickson White's resignation as history professor, 1885-06-17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Proceedings of the Associate Alumni, 1884-1903 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Annotated/Signed Pamphlets, 1887-1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1894-1903 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Class Banquet programs, 1887-1903 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Including from the ? Association
- Cornell view books, 1891-1904 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Duplicates.
- Epidemic pamphlets, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cornell pamphlets, 1868-1904 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  Memorial exercises, invitations to events, football smoker, junior smoker, Sibley College pamphlets, Glee Club, Banjo and Mandolin club, Athletic Association bylaws, oratory competitions, Christian Association, Class of 1884 reunion booklets, and other Cornell publications and pamphlets.
- Copies of the Cornell Daily Sun, 1893 (Box 1)
- Letters from Andrew D. White to Ernest W. Huffcutt, 1884-1894 (Box 9, Folder Folder)
  Letters from Andrew D. White to Ernest W. Huffcutt suggesting that Huffcutt write history of the Cornell University, November 27, 1893, Jan. 11, 1894, August 14, 1894; relating to White's aid to Huffcutt's history of Cornell Univ. Feb. 1894; to White's relationship to Hewett's history of Cornell Univ. Feb. 1894, April 30, 1894; to student disturbances at Cascadilla, Mar. 6, 1885; to punishing officers of those classes engaged in rush, Oct. 6, 1884; to General George S. Batcheller, July 13, 1894; instructing Huffcutt on handling University business on his behalf, 1884-1885. 27 letters including resignation, all letters complete.